Matilda Asuzu

UX Designer

Greater Denver Area 225.610.5852 matildadigital+hire@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/matildaasuzu/

SUMMARY

User Experience (UX) Designer with 5+ years pinpointing and satisfying user needs through interviewing and empathizing with users. Expert at simplifying and solving complex user problems by mapping and analyzing user flows to produce intuitive, elegant interactions. Skilled at translating complex product requirements into clear user flow diagrams for data-intensive web apps and creating low and high-fidelity prototypes of possible design solutions using wireframes and mockups. Technical skills include:

Adobe Illustrator
 Sketch
 InVision
 HTML
 Python
 Django
 Git

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Functional Analyst, Digital Group - Arrow Electronics, Englewood, CO

2018 - 2019

- Communicated product design solution in 150+ user stories, bugs, and tasks by researching user needs from 40+ stakeholders, product owners, and customer support teammates.
- Created a user journey map of a CXML procurement tool. Explained the potential purchasing process for customers to a leadership team of 6+ product managers. Created shared understanding of user needs and technical requirements for software development.
- Guided the product delivery for \$1.5M+ upgrade and optimization of enterprise Sitecore
 content management system (CMS) and the re-architecture of front-end (FE) web
 application using Angular 5 and Javascript Services (JSS).

UX Engineering Intern, Web Engineering - Occipital, Boulder, CO

2017 - 2018

- Generated \$22K+ revenue by developing an A/B tested product upsell feature.
- Supported marketing strategy by designing web UI and developing front-end for company's e-commerce website.

Technology Specialist, Digital Services - Arapahoe Libraries, Englewood, CO 2014 - 2017

- Gathered user feedback to test and improve course format to a sold-out program by researching, designing, and implementing a 4 week coding course for adults. Instructed 15+ students per course in fundamentals of software development.
- Created personalized solutions using technology services by interviewing users to understand pain points and needs.

Amazon Alexa Development Intern - Crestone Digital, Lakewood, CO

2016 - 2017

- Designed and developed the conversation/voice user interface for the Douglas County Amazon Alexa skill with a team to provide 300K+ residents on-demand updates on county news and events.
- Met Alexa Skill certification guidelines for app store approval by testing and debugging code.

Graphic Designer, AHSS Dean's Office - University of Denver, Denver, CO 2012 - 2014

- Engaged donors, alumni, and students in programming and increased program visibility within university brand by communicating organizational messages through inviting, clear design.
- Increased student outreach and engagement by designing and developing the concept and print materials for a student career services campaign.

Project manager and UX/UI designer - Contract, Remote

2012 - 2013

- Managed development of the Aerospace Alliance's promotional iOS/Android app.
- Created shared understanding of user needs and software requirements by remotely supervising and collaborating with 1 designer and 1 developer.
- Supported user retention, customer satisfaction, and marketing strategy by designing the user interface and experience for app and its content management system.

Business Systems Analyst - Mav6, LLC, Vicksburg, MS

2011 - 2012

- Designed user interface and experience for military intelligence application by analyzing user needs and collaborating with developers, designers, business analysts, and product managers.
- Created a customized, intuitive user interface and interactions for 4 web apps by wireframing, prototyping, and creating high fidelity mockups.
- Reduced time to market and satisfied user needs by generating software requirements for 5 web apps.
- Awarded merit bonuses for representing company values, showing professionalism, developing high quality technical communication, and showing dedication to work.

EDUCATION

Master of Arts (MA), Emergent Digital Practices (digital media) - University of Denver, Denver, CO

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Communication - Mississippi State University, Starkville, MS

AWARDS AND HONORS

- Research presenter, International Symposium on Electronic Arts Data visualization applications in social sciences
- Grow with Google Challenge Scholarship Udacity, for completing the mobile web specialist challenge course
- Women Who Code Boulder/Denver lightning talk presenter Intro to Amazon Alexa skill development
- Galvanize guest speaker Career overview for software developers